Víctor Ponce López



Contact

vponcelop<at>gmail.com victorponce.info Bristol, United Kingdom

Languages

Catalan ****(native), Spanish ★★★★ (native), English ****

(advanced reading/writing, fluent oral). Français ****

(intermediate reading/writing, basics oral).

Programming Languages, Libs, Tools, **Web and Environments**

Python, MATLAB, C++/C#/C, R, PyCharm, Netbeans, Eclipse, VS/VC++, SVN/GIT, Redmine, LATEX, XML, PostgreSQL, SQL, MySQL, Hive, Spark, Hadoop, CodaLab, Kaggle, Bash, PHP/HTML/CSS/JavaScript;

Deep Learning & Computer

Vision libraries and toolboxes: Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, GAN. CNN. LSTM. dlib. CUDA+CuDNN, Kinect™SDK, open{CV/NI/GL}, CNTK+; evolutionary computation and statistical pattern recognition: numpy, matplotlib, sklearn, optimtool, gatool, pmtk3, deap, pandas, statsmodel.

OS Preferences

GNU/Linux **** Windows ★★★★ MacOS **** Android ★★★★ iOS ****

short bio

I am a Research Fellow at the University College London and a Honorary Research Fellow of the Dept. of Computer Science at the University of Bristol and member of the European Laboratory for Learning and Intelligent Systems (ELLIS). I was a Research Scientist in Eurecat at the Big Data Analytics Unit. I hold a PhD at the the Dept. of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Barcelona (UB). I received my B.Sc. degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Faculty of Mathematics of UB, and my M.Sc. degree in Artificial Intelligence at the Polytechnic University of Catalonia. I was affiliated to the Computer Vision Center and the Open University of Catalonia, in the groups HuPBA and SUNAI; and the group Qarma at the Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentalle, Aix-Marseille Université.

experience

2017-Present **University College London & University of Bristol**

Bristol & London, United Kingdom Member of the European Laboratory for Learning and Intelligent Systems (ELLIS).

Barcelona, Spain

Postdoctoral Research Associate & Fellow

• Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing for Environment & Energy.

• Time-Series Prediction of Seasonal Ground Surface Deformation.

• Computer Vision for Human Activity Recognition in Home Healthcare.

• Domain Adaptation, Self-Supervised Learning, GANs, Person Re-IDentification.

2010-2017 Eurecat Technology Center of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, Open University of Catalonia, Computer Vision Center, and Dept. of Justice, Government of Catalonia

Research Scientist, PostDoc, Collaboration in Research projects, international PhD stay, 40+ scientific publications and peer-reviews, teaching and material preparation, organization/attendance on international conferences, events, and seminars.

• 4 impact factor journals, 17 conference proceedings, and 1 book chapter.

• ChaLearn Looking At People collaboration with Microsoft, NVIDIA, Google, Amazon, Disney, Facebook, Orange, MWC-GSMA.

· Research projects on human behavior analysis within real-world domains.

Past-2010 Barcelona's Council: Dept. of Education, Culture and Welfare

Software Engineer, IT Services.

education

2012-2016 Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona

Dissertation: "Evolutionary Bags of Space-Time Features for Human Analysis." Cum

Laude (spanish) and International Mention.

2010-2012 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence

Polytechnic University of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, and Rovira i Virgili University.

Dissertation: "Multi-Modal Human Gesture Recognition combining Dynamic Program-

ming and Probabilistic Methods." With Honors.

2006-2010 **B.Sc in Computer Science: Systems engineering**

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona.

Dissertation: "Analysis of Oral and Gestural Expression using an Artificial Vision Sys-

tem." With Honors.

extracurricular

2006-Present **Driving license**

1998-2004 Musical language and Piano licenses

interests

I'm a research & technology passionate. My main interests are computer vision, machine learning, and evolutionary computation for real-world applications. I like to be up to date with latest research and cutting-edge technology to foresee next future trends and needs.